<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on kate&#39;s lab notebook</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on kate&#39;s lab notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:38:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick look at the Hanmatek HO102S Portable Oscilloscope</title>
      <link>/post/hanmatek-ho102s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:38:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hanmatek-ho102s/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve recently been checking out a few options for inexpensive, DMM-form-factor oscilloscopes &amp;ndash; mostly out of a desire to be able to work on hardware from anywhere with just my tiny laptop, a tiny projector, and some minimal equipment.
Options like the Analog Discovery 2 are nice; but their readouts take up screen space; and they&#39;re often limited bandwidth &amp;ndash; so I thought I&#39;d try out a cheaper option in a DMM form factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including non-Amaranth Instances in Amaranth [repost]</title>
      <link>/post/amaranth-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 04:30:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/amaranth-instance/</guid>
      <description>A common question in the #amaranth-lang Libera.Chat channel asks how one can include a non-Amaranth component&amp;mdash;e.g. a library cell or a component from a Verilog design&amp;mdash;so it seemed worth writing up a quick note we can link to answer that.
Invoking a Component The key is to create an amaranth.Instance component, as in the following example:
m.submodules.my_component = Instance(&amp;#34;CustomFlipFlop&amp;#34;, # Attributes a_HasAsyncReset = False, # Parameters p_NumberInputs = &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, p_NumberOutputs = &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, # Inputs i_D = my_input_signal, # Ouptuts o_Q = my_output_signal, # Bidirectional / inouts io_DZ = my_tristate_pin ) The first parameter to the Instance constructor is the name of the component to be instantiated, which usually matches e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including non-nMigen Instances in nMigen</title>
      <link>/post/nmigen-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 04:30:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nmigen-instance/</guid>
      <description>A common question in the #nMigen Libera.Chat channel asks how one can include a non-nMigen component&amp;mdash;e.g. a library cell or a component from a Verilog design&amp;mdash;so it seemed worth writing up a quick note we can link to answer that.
Invoking a Component The key is to create an nmigen.Instance component, as in the following example:
m.submodules.my_component = Instance(&amp;#34;CustomFlipFlop&amp;#34;, # Attributes a_HasAsyncReset = False, # Parameters p_NumberInputs = &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, p_NumberOutputs = &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, # Inputs i_D = my_input_signal, # Ouptuts o_Q = my_output_signal, # Bidirectional / inouts io_DZ = my_tristate_pin ) The first parameter to the Instance constructor is the name of the component to be instantiated, which usually matches e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB3: why it&#39;s a bit harder than USB2</title>
      <link>/post/why-is-usb3-harder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 16:05:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-is-usb3-harder/</guid>
      <description>A few people on twitter have asked me to explain why the USB3 winds up being much harder to implement than USB2. The answer is more than will fit in a single tweet, so I thought I&#39;d put a quick-but-rough answer, here. This is by no means comprehensive; consider it a longer tweet what a tweet would be given I had more than 240 characters and a proclivity to babble. (I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corrections to: USB 3.0 Technology: Comprehensive Guide to SuperSpeed USB</title>
      <link>/post/mindshare-usb3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 17:10:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mindshare-usb3/</guid>
      <description>The MindShare book USB 3.0 Technology: Comprehensive Guide to SuperSpeed USB (ISBN-13: 978-0983646518) is a pretty decent reference for implementers of USB 3.0 / Gen1; but is published with a few factual mistakes &amp;ndash; places where their tables incorrectly copy the standard. This notebook post is here to gather the mistakes I&#39;ve found, so I can report them the publisher all at once.
Issues thus far (page numbers for first edition):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AB07-USB3FMC: The $1.65k eval board they can&#39;t be bothered to test</title>
      <link>/post/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 07:06:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve written a bit about my look at &amp;ldquo;commercial off-the-shelf&amp;rdquo; USB3 PHY boards; and have been taking a look recently at the Design Gateway AB07-USBFMC module. It turns out that my unit has what seems to be a pretty embarrassing defect.
I&#39;ve been testing my in-progress USB3 gateware with this PHY; and I&#39;ve been running into an interesting issue: periodically, some of the raw values sent were off by a single bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AB07-USB3FMC Notes &amp; Oddities</title>
      <link>/post/ab07-usb3fmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 21:34:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ab07-usb3fmc/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re looking to play with commercial USB3 PHY evaluation hardware &amp;ndash; that is, if you&#39;re looking to get a board someone else has designed and built, rather than soldering up your own or experimenting with 5G SerDes &amp;ndash; there seem to be two options available: the HiTech Global FMC_USB3 ($795 USD), or the Design Gateway AB07-USBFMC ($1,650 USD).
  The USB3FMC sitting atop the Digilent Nexys Video FPGA board   Thanks to Tim Ansell, I&#39;ve been able to get my hands on the AB07-USBFMC; this quick post summarizes my findings so far working with the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary: ECP5 SerDes Out-Of-Band Tx/Rx</title>
      <link>/post/serdes-oob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 10:04:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/serdes-oob/</guid>
      <description>This post is a summary of the findings from my look at using the ECP5 SerDes for USB3 LFPS for quick reference of how to use the ECP5 SerDes semi-documented out-of-band I/O features.
Quick summary:
 In addition to using the ECP5&#39;s SerDes pins to drive the SerDes; the SerDes Tx/Rx pins can also be used as Low-Data-Rate (LDR) outputs/inputs while the SerDes is in use. This is intended to allow transmission/receipt of out-of-band signals in addition to normal SerDes operation; and thus requires a configured SerDes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB3 LFPS Using ECP5 SerDes I/O</title>
      <link>/post/serdes-lfps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 11:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/serdes-lfps/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&#39;ve been developing a USB3 stack, and a USB3 frontend using the ECP5 SerDes. The ECP5 SerDes seems almost perfect for USB3, which shares many of its implementation details with PCIe. However, there are a couple of hitches.
The more difficult to deal with is support for USB3&#39;s Low Frequency Periodic Signaling (LFPS). LFPS carries small bursts of information via a slow, out-of-band signal, meant to be used before the high-speed USB3 link is established:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>